Seward, Ralph T. Papers 5328
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Ralph T. Seward Papers
1949-1966
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seward, Ralph T.
5328
30.5 cubic feet
30.5 linear ft.
Decisions, photographs, proceedings.
Includes over 1000 arbitration and mediation awards, decisions, and related documents, primarily for cases in the following industries: steel, electronics, auto, transportation, meatpacking, manufacturing, and communications. Also include documents relating to two boards of the National Mediation Service which Seward chaired (Emergency Board Number 176 and Arbitration Board No. 282).
2294712
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 28, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Arbitrator and mediator; member, National Mediation Service, National Defense Mediation Board; impartial umpire for cases involving the dairy, auto and steel industries, among others.
Ralph Seward (BA., Cornell University, 1927; MA., New York University, 1931); LLB., Columbia University, 1935) served as an attorney with the National Labor Relations Board (1936-1937) and was executive secretary (1937-1939) and general counsel (1939) of the New York State Labor Relations Board. He also served as chairman of the Board of Immigration Appeals, US Department of Justice (1939-1941), as executive secretary, National Defense Mediation Board (1941-1942), and as associate public member of the US National War Labor Board (1942) before going into private practice as an arbitrator and mediator. In addition to chairing two Emergency Boards of the National Mediation Service, Seward was impartial chairman for the metropoitan New York milk industry (1942-1944); impartial umpire for General Motors Corporation and the United Automobile Workers (1944-1947); chairman of the Board of Conciliation and Arbitration of United States Steel Corporation and United Steelworkers of America (1947-1949); impartial umpire for International Harvester Company and United Farm Equipment and Metal Workers of America (1949-1951); impartial umpire for Bethlehem Steel Corporation and the United Steelworkers of America (1952); and arbitrator and/or mediator in various other cases.
Scope and Contents
Series I:
Consists of documentation for cases arbitrated and mediated by Seward, relating to the following industries: steel, aluminum, shipbuilding, manufacturing, communications, chemical, electronics, construction, textile, rubber, meatpacking, and retail food. Materials include decisions and awards, hearings and proceedings, briefs, and exhibits used as evidence. Also includes correspondence relating to cases.
Files on major cases include those for Allegheny Ludlum Steel vs. United Steelworkers of America (USWA) (1950, 1954-1959) on issues of wage incentives, seniority, layoff procedures, severance pay, contract violation, hours of work, waste, job classification, the relation of state laws to collective agreements, pensions, reinstatement, retroactive pay, job location, and the enforcement of contracts; American Radiator and Standard Sanitary Corporation vs. United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (UBCJA) (1952) on the reissue of wage rates; Armco Steel Corporation vs. USWA (1955-1956, 1960) on the issues of wage incentives, work schedules, position descriptions, non-union labor, job displacement, and grievance procedures; A.O. Smith Corporation of Texas vs. USWA (1959) on the issues of dismissal, misrepresentation of physical capacity, and job location.
Other cases include Baltimore Motor Coach Company vs. Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America (1952) on the issues of dismissal, guaranteed employment, seniority, and union encouragement of members to refuse to work; Bethlehem Steel Corporation vs. Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America (IUMSWA) (1952) on issues of job classification, wage rates, work rules, company confiscation of employee property without compensation, and absenteeism; and Capital Airlines Corporation vs. International Association of Machinists (IAM) (1955-1956, 1960) on issues of subcontracting of work, dismissal, intoxication, and employee psychiatric problems.
Other cases include Crucibble Steel Company of America vs. USWA (1950-1951) on issues of job classification, work rules, overtime pay, seniority, hiring policies, job description, work assignment, job displacement, layoff, and composition of bargaining unit; Detroit Steel Company vs. USWA (1953) on issues of health, safety, and size of work group; Full-Fashioned Hosiery Manufacturers of America vs. American Federation of Full-Fashioned Hosiery Workers (1952) on the issue of wage rates; Kaiser Steel Corporation vs. USWA (1956, 1958) on issues of incentive pay and wage rates; Kaiser Aluminum and Chemical Corporation vs. USWA (1958) on issues of work assignment and job description; and Kelly Springfield Tire Company vs. United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum, and Plastic Workers (1952-1953) on issues of incentive pay, subcontracting of work, reporting pay, and wage rates.
Other cases include L.F. Granmes and Sons, Inc., vs. USWA on issues of insubordination, tardiness, intoxication, and dismissal; New York Photo-Engravers and Publishers Association of New York City vs. New York Photo-Engravers Union (1954) on the issues of work stoppage benefits, wage rates, and hours; New York Publishers Association vs. New York Photo-Engravers Union (1953) on issues of wage rates and job classifications; New York and New Jersey Milk Distributors Committee vs. Milk Wagon Drivers Union of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America (IBT) (1943) on issues of work schedule, overtime pay, maximum wholesale load, seniority, managerial prerogatives, dismissal, grievance procedures, and rights of shop stewards; Pittsburgh Post-Gazette et al. vs. Pittsburgh Newspaper Guild et al. (1951-1952) on issues of work stoppage, lockout, and compensation during work stoppage; and Pittsburgh Steel Company vs. USWA (1949-1952) on issues of job description, work assignment, work force size, work stoppage, safety, wage incentives, and job classification.
Other cases include Sun Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Company vs. IUMSWA (1944) on issues of dismissal, incentive pay systems, work during meal period, and job performance, intoxication, and use of voluntary company police; Swift and Company vs. United Packinghouse Workers of America (1950-1952, 1955) on issues of vacation pay, disability benefits, absenteeism, layoff, work assignment, relief work, employee theft, racial and sexual discrimination, improper personal conduct, wage rates, job classification, job description, hours of work, overtime pay, absenteeism, and insubordination; Swift and Company vs. United Construction Workers and United Mine Workers of America (1952) on the issues of implementation of previous grievance award and back pay; Swift and Company vs. IBT (1955, 1960) on issues of dismissal and employee theft; and Trans World Airlines vs. IAM (1958-1959) and Airline Dispatchers Association (1958) on issues of bargaining unit composition, bidding and job openings, work schedule, work assignment, job classification, and job displacement.
Other substantive cases include the United States Steel Corporation, American Bridge Company Division, vs. USWA (1950, 1957, 1960) on issues of unemployment compensation and layoff, overtime, seniority, job classification, wage rates, work schedule, and job description; various steel companies (US Steel, Continental, Youngstown Sheet and Tube, Republic, Inland) vs. USWA (1957) on the issue of supplementary unemployment benefits; Washington Publishers Association vs. Columbia Typographical Union (1954-1957) and Washington Photo-Engravers' Union (1959) on issues of dismissal, rest periods, interpretation of collective agreement, employer violence, insubordination, intoxication, foreman misconduct, and sick pay; Yale and Towne Manufacturing Company vs. IAM (1950) on issues of dismissal and absenteeism; and Youngstown Sheet and Tube Company vs. USWA (1950-1951) on the issue of wage rates.
Series II:
Consists of documents relating to cases arbitrated by Seward between the International Harvester Corporation and the United Farm Equipment and Metal Workers of America in the agricultural implement industry. Documents include awards and decisions, notes, correspondence, transcripts of proceedings, briefs, and exhibits filed as evidence.
Issues arbitrated include dismissal, union interference with production, absenteeism, authority of arbitrator, sick pay, employee theft, incentive pay, seniority, job classification, wage rates, bumping, work assignment, overtime, layoffs, safety, strikes, time studies, racial discrimination, improper employer records, suspensions, falsification, discrimination for union activity, demotion, promotion, sex discrimination, compensation for medical appointment, holiday pay, composition of the bargaining unit, job displacement, vacation, sabotage, violence, employment testing, shop steward suspension for instigating strike, back pay, retroactive pay, arbitrator prerogatives, insubordination, work performance, and show-up pay.
Series III:
Consists of documents relating to the case of "Certain Carriers represented by the Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committees vs. Certain of their Employees represented by the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen, and Switchmen's Union of North America" (1963) arbitrated by the National Mediation Board, Arbitration Board 282, headed by Seward.
Specifically, the series contains the following materials relating to the formation and operations of Arbitration Board 282: statements by representatives of the unions and railroads; correspondence between representatives of the unions and railroads and Seward; exhibits filed by railroads and unions, including maps, graphs, charts, copies of employee rules and regulations, financial records of various railroads, accident records, professional studies relating to the necessity of firemen on diesel powered yard and freight trains, blueprints, manning and employment records, and previous arbitration awards; transcript of proceedings before the Board: statements of the final award by Henry E. Gilbert and R.H. McDonald (employee representatives on the Board), by employer representatives on the Board, and by neutral members of the Board; transcript of the Board award; statement of the Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen on the meaning and application of the award; statement by Willard Wirtz (secretary of labor) on the necessity of a negotiated settlement; and transcript of a joint resolution of Congress calling the Board into existence (1963).
Also includes the following court decisions relating to the implementation and interpretation of the Board award: United States District Court, District of Columbia, in "Re Certain Carriers represented by the Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committees vs. Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad Company"; United States District Court, District of Columbia, "Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen vs. Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad Company"; and United States District Court, District of Columbia, "Certain Carriers represented by the Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committees vs. Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen, Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen, and Switchmen's Union of North America."
Also includes United States Supreme Court decision in the case of "Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen, and Switchmen's Union of North America vs. Certain Carriers represented by the Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committees" (1966).
Includes, as well, United States Senate hearings on the administration of Public Law 88-108, establishing Arbitration Board No. 282, including numerous statements by witnesses testifying before the Board.
Also includes interpretations rendered by reconvened Arbitration Board No. 282 (1964-1965), including numerous questions submitted by railroads and unions.
Finally, includes report of the National Joint Board, established by Arbitration Board No. 282, entitled "Experience in Freight and Yard Service with and without the Employment of Firemen" (1966).
Series IV:
Consists of documents relating to cases arbitrated by Seward between General Motors, Frigidaire Division and various unions in the electric industry. Documents include awards and decisions, correspondence, proceeding, briefs, and exhibits filed as evidence.
Consists specifically of awards for General Motors, Frigidaire Division vs. the following: International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers (1949-1953) on issues of job classification, wage rates, seniority, dismissal, absenteeism, overtime, reporting pay, disciplinary suspension, insubordination, comparable pay for comparable work, employee theft, tardiness, sick leave, work assignment, work performance, back pay, equalization of work, holiday pay, overtime pay, incentive pay, violence, intoxication, employee debts, employer control of employee actions during meal period, pregnancy leave, work schedule, falsification, job description, and bumping; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (1949) on issues of job classification, wage rates, work assignment, dismissal, falsification, intoxication, absenteeism, disciplinary suspension, overtime, sick leave, holiday work, back pay, seniority, employee theft, and job description; and United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (1951) on the issue of cost-of-living adjustments.
Series V:
Chairman's files, consisting of correspondence, hearings transcripts, statements and exhibits.
Specifically, includes a copy of a letter from Francis O'Neill (chairman, National Mediation Board) to President Richard M. Nixon declaring that an emergency existed and enclosing a proposed draft of an executive order to create the Emergency Board to deal with the dispute; the final executive order creating the Board; Board hearings (3 vol.); numerous labor and management exhibits filed with the Board, including a statement by William Winpisinger (vice-president, International Association of Machinists) describing work done by his members who worked for railroads; and a copy of the Board's award.
Also various documents on previous shop craft disputes including a copy of a US Department of Labor publication, THE RAILROAD SHOPCRAFT FACTFINDING STUDY (1968) as well as copies of agreements between the following parties: National Railway Labor Conference and Eastern, Western and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committees and employees of such carriers, represented by the organizations comprised the Railway Employees Department, AFL-CIO (1964); railroads represented by the Eastern, Western and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committee and employees of such railroads represented by the Employees National Conference Committees of eleven cooperating railway labor organizations (1960); and carriers represented by the National Railway Conference and Regional Carrier Conference Committees and the International Association of Machinists, the Sheet Metal Workers, the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, and the International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers and Helpers (1969).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5069: U.S. Wage Stabilization Board 1952 United Steelworkers of America Case 5113: Ralph T. Seward Arbitration Transcripts and Exhibits 5700: Ralph T. Seward Additional Arbitration Files 5779: Ralph T. Seward Additional Arbitration Files 5970: Ralph Seward Additional Papers
Arrangement
Series I: Arbitration Cases, General
Series II: Arbitration Cases, International Harvester
Series III: Arbitration Cases, Railroad
Series IV: Arbitration Cases, General Motors
Series V: Chairman's Files
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Cases; Arbitrators, Industrial.; Mediation and conciliation, Industrial -- United States -- Cases; Sex discrimination against women -- United States; Absenteeism. Arbitration, Industrial. United States; Alcohol abuse. Arbitration, Industrial. United States; Arbitration, Industrial. Agricultural machine industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Airlines. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Aluminum industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Automobile industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Chemical industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Construction industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Electric industries. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Electronic industries. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Food industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Grocery trade. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Hosiery industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Meat industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Motor bus lines. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Motor truck driving. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Newspaper publishing. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Railroads. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Railroads. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Rubber industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Shipbuilding industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Steel industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Telecommunication. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Textile industry. United States.; Arbitration, Industrial. Transportation. United States.; Bargaining unit. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Collective labor agreements. Railroads. United States.; Contracting out. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Discrimination in employment. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Employee fringe benefits. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Employee rights. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Employees, Dismissal of. Arbitration, Industrial. Illinois.; Employees, Dismissal of. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Employment tests. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Grievance procedures. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Hours of labor. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Industrial safety. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Job descriptions. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Job vacancies. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Labor discipline. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Labor disputes. Railroads. United States.; Labor injunction. Railroads. United States.; Labor productivity. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Labor productivity. Railroads. United States.; Layoffs. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Management rights. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Mediation and conciliation, Industrial. Railroads. United States.; Misconduct. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Performance appraisal. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Position classification. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Promotions. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Promotions. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Railroad employees, Afro-American.; Railroads. Safety regulations. United States.; Railroads. United States. Accidents.; Railroads. United States. Full crew rules.; Railroads. United States. Manpower planning.; Railroads. United States. Personnel management.; Railroads. United States. Sanitation.; Railroads. United States. State supervision.; Retirement. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Seniority, Employee. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Strikes and lockouts. Agricultural machine industry. United States.; Strikes and lockouts. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Trade-union representatives. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Trade-union security. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Trade-unions. Railroads. United States.; Trade-unions. United States. Afro-American membership.; Unfair labor practices. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Wages. Agricultural machine industry. United States.; Wages. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Wages. Electric industries. United States.; Wages. Mediation and conciliation, Industrial. United States.; Wages. Railroads. United States.; Wages. Steel industry. United States.; Work assignment. Mediation and conciliation, Industrial. United States.; Work assignments. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Work rules. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Work rules. Mediation and conciliation, Industrial. United States.; Davidson, Ray E.; Dungan, Ralph A. (Ralph Anthony), 1923-2013; Gilbert, Henry E., 1906-; Luna, Charles, 1906-; McDonald, R. H.; Seward, Ralph T. (Ralph Theodore), 1907-; Speirs, Neil P.; Winpisinger, William W.; Wirtz, Willard, 1912-; Wolfe, James E.; Airline Dispatchers Association; Allegheny Ludlum Steel Corporation; Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America; American Bridge Company; American Federation of Full-Fashioned Hosiery Workers; ARMCO Steel Corporation; Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company; Atlantic Coast Line Company; Bethlehem Steel Corporation; Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen; Brotherhood of Railway, Airline and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees; Capital Airlines Corporation; Central of New Jersey Railroad Company; Chesapeake & Ohio Railway Company; Chicago and North Western Railway Company; Chicago, Burlington & Quincy Railroad Company; Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway Company; Columbia Typographical Union; Crucible Steel Company of America; Denver & Rio Grande Western Railroad Company; Detroit Steel Company; Eastern Carriers' Conference Committee; Full-Fashioned Hosiery Manufacturers of America; General Motors Corporation. Frigidaire Division.; Illinois Central Railroad Company; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; Inland Steel Company; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers; International Association of Machinists; International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers.; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America; International Harvester Company; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers.; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; Jones & Laughlin Steel Company; Kaiser Steel Corporation; Kelly Springfield Tire Company; L.F. Granmes and Sons, Inc.; Lithographers and Photoengravers International Union; Missouri Pacific Railroad Company; National Railway Labor Conference (U.S.); New York and New Jersey Milk Distributors Committee; New York Central Railroad; Nickel Plate Railroad; Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen; Panhandle & Santa Fe Railway; Pennsylvania Railroad; Pittsburgh Newspaper Guild; Pittsburgh Post-Gazette; Pittsburgh Steel Company; Publishers' Association of New York City; Republic Steel Corporation; Seaboard Air Line Railroad; Sheet Metal Workers' International Association; Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committee; Southern Pacific Company; St. Louis Southwestern Railway Company; Swift and Company; Switchmen's Union of North America; Texas and Pacific Railroad; Trans World Airlines, Inc.; Union Pacific Railway Company; United Construction Workers; United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America; United Farm Equipment and Metal Workers of America; United Packinghouse Workers of America; United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum, and Plastic Workers; United States Steel Corporation; United States. Emergency Board No. 176.; United States. National Mediation Board; United States. Wage Stabilization Board.; United Steelworkers of America; Washington Publishers' Association; Western Carriers' Conference Committee; Youngstown Sheet and Tube Company